BECON DANIEL O.

Mr., Engr, Dev

283, Ifite Road, Awka, Anambra +2348037026969 daffydanni@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Communication, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Management, Microsoft Excel, and Engineering. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused in metallurgical/material engineering from Nnamdi Azikiwe University.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Web Development
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript Developer
- Bootstrap
- ReactJS Developer

- Risk Management
- Material Engineering
- Performance Management
- Team Building and Leadership
- Complex Problem-solving Abilities
- Interpersonal Communication Skills

Technical Skills: Microsoft Office Suite, MS Excel Proficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bonitas Group LTD, Awka Web Developer

Jan. 2022-Date

- Bringing UI to life.
- Maintaining code base in the development process.
- Developing an effective and reusable code base.
- Monitoring the company's website performance using established corporate business performance metrics.
- Providing leadership in the development of staff policies, training, and performance measurement.

Key Accomplishments

- Successfully set up the frontend design for the GVE project.
- Involvement in the frontend design for the HSE App.
- Finished a course on Coursera for Frontend Development

Stanel Group PLC, Awka Customer Associate

Mar. 2018-Jan. 2021

- Facilitated positive relationships with customers and clients.
- Monitored the implementation of discharging and offloading of products.
- Optimized the handling of cash and deposit relationships and initiated appropriate strategies to enhance cash positioning.

- Implemented a reliable work process to help customers and colleagues have a good working environment.
- Ensured appropriate financial risk, accounting, and procedures of the company.

Key Accomplishments

• Successfully drove a culture of accountability in managing the business by creating an accountability reputation for the company.

Arizona Digital LTD, Lagos

Office Assistant

Jun. 2012-Nov. 2014

- Performing general office tasks such as filing, phones, and photocopying.
- Managing calendars, scheduling appointments, and coordinating meetings.
- Creating and formatting documents, such as reports and presentations.
- Involved actively in the strategy phase and the eventual kick-off of the product to clients.
- Providing customer service, including responding to inquiries and handling complaints.

Key Accomplishments

- Advanced my Microsoft skills.
- My organizational abilities improved.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Industrial Training (Field Engineer); Swiss Biostat Group, Lagos.

July 2019—Dec. 2019
Sales Personnel; Chi Limited Plc, Lagos

Nov2011—April 2011

EDUCATION

BSc. in Metallurgical and Material Engineering, Nnamdi Azikiwe	2021
University, Awka	
SSCE.; Command Day Secondary School Oshodi, Lagos	2011

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera; Frontend Development course by Meta 2022

REFERENCES

Available on request